SASCHA ANDEWEG

LINGUISTIC DATA ANALYST / JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER / GRAPHIC DESIGNER /

20 Hawthorn Crescent Forest Glen, P61K253 Fermoy, Co. Cork T: 089 7028 790 E: sascha@designed.irish

As a **linguistic data analyst/modeler in AI/ML** I optimize the processes that improve the customer's experience. Improving accuracy, debugging, improving workflows, adding data for new functionality and clarifying and improving guidelines; the projects I work on for one of the big tech multinationals have a big impact on how users define the brand. Within the team I also train new hires and function as point of contact for several administrative tasks and project related matters. Due to a non disclosure contract I cannot further elaborate on the specifics of the role

In September 2020 I graduated from the Code Institute with second class honors in **Full Stack Software Development**. I developed problem solving skills and use the principles of coding as is done in the industry today. In four milestone projects I did my own research, UX design, used HTML and CSS in user centric frontend development, used JavaScript in an interactive frontend development project, Python in a data centric development project that includes a MongoDB database and finally built a full stack e-commerce website using the Django framework, Stripe payments, a Postgres database and user profiles. Version control was done with GitHub and deployment of static assets to AWS S3 bucket and Heroku to run the Python project. This resulted in a ready to use e-commerce website for a music festival.

Until 2016 I lived and worked in the Netherlands. As a **web designer**, **graphic designer** and **prepress specialist** I brought concepts to end product distribution or deployment. Designing and producing material for print and web, often in close collaboration with the client, resulted in long lasting professional, and profitable, relationships and many, sometimes memorable, products. My responsibility of being the headquarter's on-site support contact for all IT-related matters helped the continuity and optimization of all the processes of the offices, prepress department and the printing and finishing department.

I look forward to successfully evolve into a role that may require the skills and qualities I have developed.

EXPERIENCE

2016 - present GLOBETECH LTD.

Linguistic Data Analyst

Linguistic analysis and modelling for artificial intelligence and machine learning. Due to a non-disclosure contract I cannot share specific details about the position.

2004- present

FESTIVAL VAN ZEEUWSCH-VLAANDEREN

Web Designer - Graphic Designer

I built the <u>website</u> for a classical music festival since the late nineties when working for the TekstBeeld Group. In consultation with my former employer Mr. Bareman I continued this after relocating to Ireland.

1985 - 2016

DRUKKERIJ BAREMAN / TEKSTBEELD GROEP Prepress s

Prepress specialist / Graphic Designer

Graphic Designer

Good knowledge of the ins and outs of Adobe CC design and photo-editing software and MS Office applications helped me to deliver results quickly and easily make design-changes when required. I have the descernment to know when to use creativity and innovation or follow strict guidelines where corporate styles demand it.

I have excellent time management, communication and organisational skills to meet deadlines and work with the in-house printing department. Good understanding of the latest trends and their role within the commercial environment of our clients and our own business helped me to make design and or content decisions with the client. I have always valued a personal approach towards clients to build long lasting relationships.

Prepress

Preparing graphic designs for printing (offset and digital), inpositioning and offset-plate making.

Operating digital printers (large format inkjet and laser). In these roles precision and speed were crucial to avoid operational delays and costly mistakes in production.

Web Design

I made accurate and competitive quotations, a viable planning, attractive designs, ensured catchy and professional copywriting and bug free deployment. Further responsibilities were managing the maintenance contracts, support and any other form of after care.

• IT-support

Working in head quarters I dealt with the on-site IT-support (Windows-servers, networking, security, hardware support). I had an advisory role for aquiring computer hard- and software at the graphic design department.

Sales and publishing

I produced the lay-out for a local magazine, managed/coordinated the editorial content and acquisition of advertisements. Occasionally I would assist in the acquisition of advertisements by phone and in writing editorial material.

SASCHA ANDEWEG

LINGUISTIC DATA ANALYST / JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER / GRAPHIC DESIGNER /

2006 - 2016 RAMMELOO COMMUNICATIONS Graphic Designer

As a freelancer I produced the layout, including many of the adverts, of a local paper and created high quality printed presentation material to push sales.

SKILLS

- Data Analysis Managing data for AI/ML due to non-disclosure contract I cannot elaborate on specifics
- Junior Full Stack Software Developer Trained in:
 - User Centric Frontend Development using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and the principles of UX design
 - Interactive Frontend Development with JavaScript, testdriven development using Jasmine, JQuery, JSON, using API's
 - Data Centric Development with Python, framework Flask, MySQL and MongoDB database
 - Full Stack Frameworks with Django, Postgres, AWS S3, Github, Stripe payment inplementation
- Graphic Design Well versed in the Adobe CC software and Microsoft Office and all processes to prepare designs for printing

EDUCATION

Diploma Second Class Honours DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CodeInstitute, Dublin, Ireland

WORKSHOP COLUMN WRITING Marjon Sarneel. The Netherlands
Certificate TRAINING 'EXPERT IN SALES' Kenneth Smit. The Netherlands
Certificate DREAMWEAVER/FLASH COURSE GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
Certificate BASIC WEBDESIGN AND HTML GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
Diploma GRAPHIC TECHNICIAN PREPRESS GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands

VOLUNTEERING

- present

I manage the exchange of weekly public talks for a local audience between various locations in Ireland. I also participate as a public speaker myself.

(SOCIAL) MEDIA

- LinkedIn
- Portfolio

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

- Improvised music. This type of creativity and communication gives me energy and fresh ideas. The most magical form of communication.
- Graphic Design. Only well designed a message will be clear to all. I love how typographically well presented material can be a joy to look at and becomes a joy to take in.
- Photography. Since my drawing and painting abilities are limited, capturing the moment in a photo is the next best thing for me.
- The power of language. Thoughout my entire professional career language has been the main attribute. The design of text, how it can move people, how it can be used technically... and how my words might make you consider me for the role I'm interested in.